wilkes.edu 2014-06-27

# Wilkes Privacy

| 

**Privacy Policy**  
Wilkes University takes privacy issues seriously, and will never knowingly share, sell, or rent your personal information with any individual, company, or organization without your advance permission, or unless ordered by a court of law.  The following privacy policy explains the information we collect when you visit this site and how we use this information. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully so you understand our privacy practices.

**Information Wilkes University Collects**  
Wilkes University collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. The University also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by Wilkes University. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by Wilkes University for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Wilkes.edu Web site.

**Use of your Personal Information**  
Information collected by Wilkes University is used to provide information regarding the university that you request, for the application process and to inform you of other products, services or events available from Wilkes University and its official affiliates.   An official affiliate is a third-party service provider which the University may contract with to provide services on our behalf, including but not limited to: Social Networking, hosting, web analytics, lead generation, academic, business, career or financial services. 

In some circumstances Wilkes University contracts with third party service providers to gather and/or deliver information. We knowingly contract only with organizations and companies whose guidelines and standards are in accordance with those of Wilkes University. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Wilkes University, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Wilkes University will not intentionally sell, rent, lease, share or distribute your personal information to third parties, except as required by law or university policy.  Information submitted to Wilkes University is available only to those who manage the information for the purpose of conducting business with Wilkes University and its official affiliates.

**Security of your Personal Information**  
Wilkes University uses best efforts to secure your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. The University secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. As effective as encryption technology is, however, no security system is completely impenetrable, so we cannot guarantee absolute security of our database, nor can we guarantee that information you supply won’t be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet.

**Use of “Cookies”**  
The Wilkes University website (and possibly those of official affiliates) may use “cookies” to help personalize your online experience.  If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our website, you can set your browser to refuse all cookies that are stored on your computer. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use or navigate through most parts of our website, although some functionality may be lost.

**Protecting Children's Privacy**  
If we learn that a child under age 13 has provided personally identifiable information to our sites, we will promptly remove this from our files. For more on children's privacy rights, read about the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act at the FTC's website.

**Changing Your Information**  
If an individual needs to modify, delete information submitted he/she should email Wilkes University at [unsubscribe@wilkes.edu](mailto:unsubscribe@wilkes.edu). Furthermore, if an individual would like to opt-out after submitting information he/she should also send an email to [unsubscribe@wilkes.edu](mailto:unsubscribe@wilkes.edu).

|
